Liangyawei Kuang

Room 1007-24, Research Postgraduate Hub, HKUST, Clear Water Bay, Kowloon, Hong Kong. lkuang@connect.ust.hk https://klyw1998.github.io/LiangyaweiKuang/ https://www.deadsecond.com

Introduction

I am a postgraduate researcher at the Hong Kong University of Science and Technology (HKUST). My research goal is to develop learning algorithms and techniques that could endow machines and systems with greater autonomy and intelligence to acquire the skills for executing complex tasks. I am interested in the intersection of reinforcement learning, decision-theoretic planning, and multi-agent systems. Currently, I focus on solving Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning problems under scalability and reliability consideration & diving theoretical and algorithmic foundation of Reinforcement Learning.

Research Experience

Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning

Apr. 2021 - present

Coursework and literature review from Multi-Agent Planning Under Uncertainty to Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning (MARL). Implementing basic algorithms on single-agent Planning, single-agent Reinforcement Learning (RL), and MARL. For researchers on MARL, the goal is to solve some key challenges in MARL, including Non-Stationarity, Non-Unique Learning Goals, and Scalability.

URL https://github.com/klyw1998/Implementation-of-RL-Algorithms

Advisor: Prof. Fangzhen Lin

Multi-Agent Systems

Dec. 2021 - present

Multi-Agent Systems (MAS) research is to study systems that consist of a group of agents that can potentially interact with each other. It was called Distributed Artificial Intelligence which is a classical interdiscipline research area, including game theory, control, and learning. It re-emerged in recent years with the rising of advanced learning techniques

URL https://github.com/klyw1998/Multi-Agent-Systems

Advisor: Prof. Fangzhen Lin

Education

HKUST, Hong Kong, China

Aug. 2021 - present

Master of Philosophy in Individualized Interdisciplinary Program

(Robotics and Autonomous Systems)

Advisor: Prof. Fangzhen Lin

HKUST (Guangzhou), Guangzhou, China

Sept. 2022 - Dec. 2022

Cross Campus Virtual Exchange (Remote)

Northeastern University, MA, U.S.A.

Jul. 2020 - Jun. 2021

Thesis-based Master of Computer Engineering in Computer Vision, Machine Learning and Algorithms (degree discontinued)

University of California, Irvine, CA, U.S.A. Aug. 2019 - Jun. 2020 Final year visiting in Electrical Engineering & Computer Science Department

Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Hong Kong, China Jan. 2019 - Jun. 2019 One-semester exchange in Mechanical Engineering Department

Harbin Institute of Technology, Harbin, China

Aug. 2016 - Jun. 2020

Bachelor of Engineering in Mechatronics Engineering

Spring 2022 **Teaching** HKUST, Lecturer Multi-Robot Systems Course link: https://github.com/klyw1998/Multi-Robot-Systems Northeastern University, Teaching Assistant Fall 2020 EECS 7311: Two Dimensional Signal and Image Processing Skills Python, C/C++, MATLAB, R, SQL, Java **Programming** Libraries NumPy, Matplotlib, Scikit-Learn, OpenAI Gym, PyTorch, TensorFlow2 Languages Mandarin, Classical Chinese, English (IELTS: 7), Beginner on Latin Others LATEX, Linux, ROS, Docker, Vim, Microsoft Office **Invited Talks** Cooperative Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning 2022 Seminar in Robotics and Autonomous Systems Thrust, System Hub, HKUST(Guangzhou) On-Campus Food Delivery System via Multi-Agent Pathfinding, HKUST **Projects** 2021 Project page: https://github.com/klyw1998/Multi-Agent-Pathfinding Home Credit Default Risk competition at Kaggle, HKUST 2022 Ranked top 14% (Bronze Medal level) based on Machine Learning techniques. This project is carried out by only two participants in less than one week's work! Project page: https://github.com/klyw1998/Statistical-Machine-Learning Postgraduate Studentship, HKUST 2021 - 2023 Honours Meritorious Winner (top 6% in 2019), Mathematical Contest in Modeling 2019 Outstanding Student Leader, Harbin Institute of Technology 2017 & 2018 Second Class Scholarship, Harbin Institute of Technology 2017 & 2018 SMC Scholarship, Harbin Institute of Technology 2017